Sujith Gopinath

Sr. Frontend Developer

A self-taught developer with 6+ years of experience in architecting and building the frontend applications for B2B and B2C startups (logistics, food delivery, mobility service-based companies, etc), I have designed and developed over 15 advanced application from use-cases and functional requirements. At the moment, I am building applications for stealth mode startups and also contributing to open-source projects (Dev.to, etc).

$>\!\!<$	sujithgnth@gmail.com
	(+91) 9741978785
in	linkedin.com/in/sujithnath
0	github.com/sujithnath

https://sujithnath.github.io/sujithnath/

SKILLS

sujeith-gopi-nath

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Frontend Engineer - [Self Employed]

Stack: React + Redux Hooks, TypeScript, GraphQI + Apollo, Next.JS, Node, Webpack, Testing, StoryBook

12/2019 - Present

Currently consulting various startups

- Built inspection feature and design system for a stealth mobility startup resulting in the reduction of manual work.
- Developed employee management admin panel and scalable survey form improving internal operating efficiency by over 40%.
- Built an isomorphic SPA HR application, features including admin page, assigning and tracking interview products using nextis.
- Built a Crypto listing product (coincodecap.com), another version of product hunt for crypto products
- Applications are built with custom webpack, unit testing using jest + react library, CI/CD pipeline and scalable architecture which helped the company to scale up with the industrial standard.

Reference: Gaurav (linkedin.com/in/g-agrawal/)

Sr. Frontend Engineer - Loadshare Network

Stack: React + Redux + Hooks, Node, JavaScript, TDD, Webpack, TypeScript, AWS, CI/CD pipeline

04/2018 – 09/2019 loadshare.net

Managed the whole frontend logistics application, also closely worked with designers, PM's and cross-team to understand and implement features

- Architected the platform from a legacy codebase (Angular template) to a Node + React + Redux SPA using TS, webpack, and unit test.
- Modularisation of dashboards abstraction layer for APIs, Promises, data store using redux, presentational and container components
- Improved app performance (TTI) with server rendering using with node + webpack + prefetch, splitting into assets injection, lazyloading, routing etc
- Delivered a fully functional logistics app with 13 features (audit s/m, cash on delivery, item tracking, etc) & got a Performance bar raiser award.
- Built custom components like dynamic table (in-house plugin) structure allowing customizable configuration which formed the backbone of the app.
- Took responsibility for tasks/features assigned from understanding the requirement, designing, implementation, and unit testing.

Reference: Gaurav (linkedin.com/in/g-agrawal/)

JavaScript/ES6+ React/Redux Angular/AngularJS TypeScript Node.js/Express Next.js Apollo/GraphQL Webpack HTML5/CSS3+SCSS Docker/Kubernetes TDD/Unit Testing (Jest, Enzyme, React library) StoryBook CI/CD pipeline (GitLab, CircleCI) D3.js Redis Microservices Semantics & Accessibility

PERSONAL PROJECTS

A/B testing

Shopify Notification Feature

 Using vanilla JavaScript, developing a feature to notify users about the Shopify products

Scrum/Agile

Conducted Workshops

 On Topics such as TDD, writing good unit tests and latest ES6 features (@swiggy)

Blog on medium

• Angular AOT vs JIT comparison

EDUCATION

Bachelors Engineering: Mahatma Gandhi University (08/2008 – 04/2012)

Major in Electronics of Communication

Frontend Developer - Swiggy

Stack: React + Redux, AngularJS, JavaScript, TDD, Webpack, Mobile hybrid, Node

05/2016 - 04/2018

swiggy.com

Managed the entire vendor application of Swiggy, also helped in scaling the application from 3000 to 25000 daily users

- Built vendor app for restaurant owners from scratch which included discount features, multi-step signup flow, push notification & user metrics
- Build new APIs using Node with express by integrating with microservices services
- Developed Vendor PWA utilising PRPL pattern, web APIs like ServiceWorker, IntersectionObserver and Push API
- Introduced self-diagnostic & communication system for vendors to catch browser issues improving CX by 30% & got the best performer award.
- Developed Vendor PWA utilising PRPL pattern, web APIs like ServiceWorker, IntersectionObserver and Push API
- Integrated few features into the android app serving as a mobile hybrid.
- Optimization using webpack such as split & load the chunks using prefetch and preload.
- A member of the Page Performance Team & secured 1st place in the Swiggy hackathon 2017.

Reference: Vinit Bothra (linkedin.com/in/vinitbothra/)

UI Developer - Pipemonk (Acquired by FreshDesk)

Stack: Angular 1, JavaScript, JQUERY, Bootstrap, SCSS, Webpack, Firebase, Responsive development

04/2015 - 05/2016

After internal transfer from previous company, I was tasked to maintain website (primarily SEO) and cloud integration application

- Built Pipemonk Cloud app Angular 1, A/B testing, with cross-device functionality
- Implemented application with firebase to have more control over user data
- Built Pipemonk StoreFront using the EJS template to supply dynamic pages based on user location.

Reference: Vaibav (linkedin.com/in/vaibhav-sinha1989/)

UI DEVELOPER - Appiness Interactive

Stack: JavaScript, JQUERY, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS, D3, Mobile responsive.

9/2013 - 04/2015

appinessworld.com

Early Stage Service Based Startup.

- Built visualization chart with D3.js and admin app for Schneider Electric
- Built a scalable, lightweight flash video player that became the standard video player in custom ad units
- Built responsive websites and developed a chrome plugin for the Digital SEO team.